Guide to the Frances Edna Felin Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Frances Edna Felin papers
1937-1956
1937-1940
SC0417
Felin, Frances Edna, 1909-
1 Linear feet
Collection consists of her research notes and graphs, 1937-38, from her doctoral dissertation on plankton in Searsville Lake on the Stanford campus; a typescript draft of the dissertation, 1940; and a paper on the growth of swordtails and Pacific sardine, 1956.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Felin earned her master's (1937) and her doctoral (1940) degrees in biology from Stanford University.
Description of the Collection
Collection consists of her research notes and graphs, 1937-38, from her doctoral dissertation on plankton in Searsville Lake on the Stanford campus; a typescript draft of the dissertation, 1940; and a paper on the growth of swordtails and Pacific sardine, 1956.
Access Terms
Felin, Frances Edna, 1909-; Plankton --California.; Searsville Lake (Calif.)
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1937-1956
  - Draft of her dissertation on plankton in Searsville Lake, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Growth Rates and Food Levels; Sources Cited for notes on Fish, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Field Notes on Plankton, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notes on Plankton Count at Searsville Lake, 1937 May-June (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notes on Plankton Count at Searsville Lake, 1937 September-December (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notes on Plankton Count at Searsville Lake, 1938 January-May (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Plankton Count at Searsville Lake, 1938 May-June (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notes on Plankton Count at Searsville Lake, 1938 July-August (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Data on Plankton from Searsville Lake, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notes on Plankton at the Bottom of Searsville Lake, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Graphs on Plankton Data from Searsville Lake, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Report on the Study of Plankton, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Instructions on Stream, Lake, and Game Survey, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript on Growth of Swordtails and Pacific Sardine, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 6)